

# Gianluca Zoni

#### INTERACTION DESIGNER • CREATIVE DEVELOPER

I'm an ambitious designer fueled by a love for the outdoors and an obsession for all things tech. I'm driven by the desire to create meaningful experiences to make the world a tiny bit better.

### **Education**

Politecnico di Milano Milano Milano

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN DIGITAL AND INTERACTION DESIGN
Sep. 2022 - Now

Politecnico di Milano Milano Milano

Bachelor's Degree in Communication Design Sep. 2019 - Jul. 2022

# **Experience**

#### **PoliMovies Cinematography & Film Making Association**

Milan, Italy

CO-FOUNDER & VICE-PRESIDENT

Jun. 2023 - Present

PoliMovies is the first designers-led student association at Politecnico di Milano, dedicated to creating a vibrant community of aspiring filmmakers and cinephiles.

Our mission is to promote cinematography culture to students through curated movie screenings and cine forums, hands-on workshops to develop storytelling and film production skills, and collaborative production projects. We provide opportunities for members to explore the art and craft of filmmaking, develop their skills, and showcase their creative talents.

- Coordinated licensing agreement for the screening of movies
- · Managing relations with entities and brands collaboration for the organization of events
- Producer and Post Production Supervisor for the projects led by the association

Politecnico di Milano Milano Milano

STUDENT AMBASSADOR Apr. 2023 - Present

· Counseling students in discovering the field of Digital and Interaction Design and getting to know life at Politecnico di Milano

Softec S.p.A. Milan, Italy

**UI DESIGNER** *May.* 2022 - Jul. 2022

Internship in the Marketing and Design department of the company

Assisted the Design team in transitioning from Sketch to Figma

Politecnico di Milano Milano Milano

IT CONSULTANT & INNOVATIVE TECHNOLOGIES TUTOR

Mar. 2021 - Dec. 2021

Collaboration with METID department in Politecnico di Milano assisting schools during the COVID-19 pandemic with distance learning, counseling teachers and students in the use of digital and innovative learning platforms

· Performed programming lessons in an elementary school utilizing a tailored educational version of the popular video game Minecraft

#### **Honors & Awards**.

2020 Winner, MESAthon Human-Computer Interaction 24h Challenge

Online

## **Publications**

A Virtual Reality experience to raise sustainability awareness within the Fashion Industry,

Proceedings of the Design Society: DESIGN Conference 2024 by Cambridge University Press

In Press

## Skills

2024

**Design Tools** Figma, Notion, Adobe Creative Suite, Blender, DaVinci Resolve

**Prototyping** Protopie, Arduino, Unity

**Front-End** HTML/CSS, Javascript, Node.js, Astro, React.js, Three.js

**Soft Skills** Leadership, Communication, Problem Solving, Time Management

Languages Italian native, English C1